shell-livewire.org 2018-09-25

# Privacy | Shell LiveWIRE UK

**What does this privacy policy cover?**

This privacy notice is to inform you regarding the use of your personal information which is collected during (a) your visit to the Shell LiveWire website; (b) your participation in the programs or projects that are part of of the Shell LiveWire program (c) your entry into the competitions run as a part of the Shell LiveWire program, such as the Top Ten Innovators Competition (the “Competitions”), (c) your vote during the term of such Competitions. This Privacy Policy complements the global Privacy Notice - Business Customers, Suppliers and Business Partners, available at www.shell.com/privacy, depending on your location. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with this Privacy Notice and the Shell Global Privacy Notice that contains more detailed information about the exercise of your individual rights.

**Who is responsible for the personal information collected on this site?**

Your personal data is controlled ultimately by Shell International Limited, a company registered in England with registered number 3075807 whose registered office is at Shell Centre, London, SE1 7NA, England.

**Special Notice - if you are under 18 years old**

Our website and programs are not aimed at children under 16 years old and we will not collect, use, provide or process in any other form any personal information of children under the age of 18 deliberately. We therefore also ask you, if you are under 16 years old, please do not send us your personal information (for example, your name, address and email address).

If you are under 16 years old and you nevertheless wish to ask a question or use this website in any way which requires you to submit your personal information please get your parent or guardian to do so on your behalf.

**Purposes of the collection of your data and what types of data we collect and process**

We collect and use your personal data for purposes related to the Shell LiveWIRE Program, for the purposes of running the Competitions and to inform you of who we are and what we do.

Depending whether you are (a) a visitor to the Shell LiveWire website (b) a participant to a Shell LiveWIRE program or project or a participant to the Competitions (the “Competition”) (c) a voter during the term of the Competitions, we will process a different scope of your personal information as we only collect and use personal information to the necessary extent.

For participants to the Projects, Programs or Competitions we may collect and process such details as e-mail address, applicant name, applicant role in business, business name and description, description of the innovation introduced in the business, the benefits introduced by the innovation.

If you are an applicant to the Competitions, please note that the following details shall be available to the visitors of the Shell LiveWIRE websites and/or voters in the Competition:

  * Name

  * Business

  * Country

  * Business Overview, depending on the nature of application or participation in the competition –.

  * Video/Transcript

If you are a voter in the Competition, please note that we will collect and process the following details solely for the purposes related to the organisation of the Competition: e-mail address and/or social media ID (if voting through the social media account).

We may use your personal information in order to:

  * respond to queries or requests submitted by you

  * process registrations, Competition entries and requests for newsletters and Competition related communications submitted by you as well as process votes submitted for the Competition

  * administer or otherwise carry out our obligations in relation to the Competition you have with us

  * where applicable assess the entries submitted as part of the Competition or the votes submitted as a part of the Competition

  * anticipate and resolve problems related to the Shell LiveWIRE program and/or the Competition.

  * Contact participants to the Competition to evaluate their progress/developments following the organisation of the Competition.

  * create products or services that may meet your needs.

In the event you would like to subscribe to our newsletter, we will only use your personal data for this purpose if you have consented to such communication

Failure to provide us with the required personal information will negatively affect your ability to participate in the Competition and our ability to communicate with you in the context of the Competition.

**What are the legal grounds for processing the personal data?**

The personal data covered by this Privacy Notice is processed: (i) in order to take steps at the request of an individual prior to participation in the Competition (ii) where it is necessary to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation to which the relevant Shell company/companies is subject to; (iii) where it is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the relevant Shell company/companies, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the individual/s; (iv) or (only if legally required) with the explicit consent of the individual.

In those cases where processing is based on consent (for instance with regard to direct marketing), and subject to applicable local law which provides otherwise, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.  This will not affect the validity of the processing prior to the withdrawal of consent.

**Transfers of personal data**

Your personal data that will be collected as a part of the Competition, may be transferred within the Shell group, including to Shell companies which may be located outside the Economic European Area (“EEA”) for the purposes detailed above. Shell ensures that these entities implement adequate levels of protection in order to safeguard your personal information and will not use your personal information for any other purposes than the ones set out in this Privacy Policy. Please note that Shell has adopted Binding Corporate Rules approved by the European Union data protection regulators as a mechanism to implement adequate levels of protection for transfers of personal data within the Shell group of companies.

In addition, the collected personal data may be transferred to selected third parties for the purposes of organising the Competition (including, but not limited to, reviewers, communication providers and collaboration tool providers), which may be located outside of the Economic European Area (“EEA”) as part of the services offered to you through our site. By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EEA or one of our service providers is located in a country outside of the EEA.

These third parties will not use your personal information for any other purposes than what we have agreed with them. Shell requests those third parties to implement adequate levels of protection in order to safeguard your personal information.

We respect your personal information and therefore, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected if we transfer your information outside of the EEA in this way. In addition, if you use our services while you are outside the EEA, your information may be transferred outside the EEA in order to provide you with those services.

Except as set out in this privacy policy, we will not disclose any personally identifiable information without your permission unless we are legally entitled or required to do so (for example, if required to do so by legal process or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime) or if we believe that such action is necessary to protect and/or defend our rights, property or personal safety and those of our users/customers or other individuals.

Please be assured that we will not use your information for any of the purposes if you have indicated that you do not wish us to use your information in this way when submitting the information or at a later stage.

We will retain your personal information only for (i) the time necessary for the organisation of the Competition; (ii) the time necessary to fulfil the purposes detailed above.

The personal information of the voters to the Competition will be retained for a maximum of 30 days upon the termination of the Competition.

The personal information provided by the participants to the Competition is retained for the purposes of contacting the participants to discuss and determine progress/developments following the completion of the Competition.

**Collection of non-personal information**

We may automatically collect non-personal information about you such as the type of internet browsers you use or the website from which you linked to our website. We may also aggregate details which you have submitted to the site (for example the town where you live). You cannot be identified from this information and it is only used to assist us in providing an effective service on this web site. We may from time to time supply third parties with this non-personal or aggregated data for uses in connection with this website.

**Interaction between you and us**

We are interested in your views, and we value feedback from our clients and visitors, we may therefore set up notice boards, newsgroups, feedback, email, forum facilities and/ or chat rooms. If at any time this website offers any chat rooms, notice board facilities, newsgroups etc we may collect the personal information that you disclose such information will be used in accordance with this privacy policy..

**Keeping our records accurate**

We aim to keep our information about you as accurate as possible. You can access your personal data, request correction or deletion of the personal data (but only where it is no longer required for a legitimate business purpose) and request that the processing of your personal data is restricted - by contacting us as set below.

**Security of your personal data**

We have implemented technology and policies with the objective of protecting your privacy from unauthorised access and improper use and will update these measures as new technology becomes available, as appropriate.

**Use of your personal information submitted to other web sites**

On our websites, we may have links to other websites or you are referred to our website through a link from another website. As you can imagine, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites. Such content is subject to their terms of use and any additional guidelines and privacy information provided in relation to that use on their website.

We recommend that you check the policy of each website you visit to better understand your rights and obligations especially when you are submitting any type of content on those third party website. Please contact the owner or operator of such website if you have any concerns or questions.

**Cookies policy**

We use the term “cookies” to refer to cookies and other similar technologies covered by the EU Directive on privacy in electronic communications. Please refer to our “Cookies Policy” for further information on the usage of cookies or similar technologies - available _[here](https://www.shell.com/cookie-policy.html)_.

**How to contact us:**

If you have any issues, queries or complaints regarding the processing of your personal data please contact us at the contact details provided below or by contacting the Shell Group Chief Privacy Officer (Data Protection Officer) at [Privacy-Office-SI@shell.com](mailto:Privacy-Office-SI@shell.com) or by mail at Shell International B.V. The Hague, The Netherlands - Trade Register, No. 27155369 Correspondence: PO Box 162, 2501 AN, The Hague. 

If you are unsatisfied with the handling of your personal data by Shell, then you have the right to lodge a complaint to your own data protection authority (we can provide you with the details upon request) or the Dutch Data Protection Authority whose address is Prins Clauslaan 60, 2595 AJ The Hague, Netherlands.  Please visit <https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en> for more information.  

Requests for information about this Privacy Policy can be _[emailed](mailto:%20enquiries@shell-livewire.com)_ to us.
